VAN-CHAN NGO

+1412-626 0329 \diamond channgo@cmu.edu \diamond van-chan.ngo(Skype) Carnegie Mellon University, 5000 Forbes Avenue, PA 15213, USA

http://channgo2203.github.io/

SUMMARY

My research activities aim at building reliable and secure computer systems by developing formal frameworks which guarantee that software satisfies formally its specification, especially embedded safety-critical software such as automotive, avionic, and health-care applications. The construction of a formal framework involves the research and knowledge of principles of programming languages, compiler design and development, and formal methods including model checking, theorem proving, and static analysis for providing formal assurances that the specification is fulfilled.

EDUCATION

INRIA, Rennes, France

August 2014

Ph.D in Computer Science & Engineering

Programming Language, Compiler, and Formal Verification of Embedded and Safety-Critical Systems First Class Honors

Université de Grenoble, Verimag, Grenoble, France

June 2008

Masters in Computer Science & Engineering

Embedded Software and Systems

French Government Scholarship, Évariste Galois Program

Hanoi University of Technology, Hanoi, Vietnam

July 2005

Engineer Degree in Computer Engineering

Information Systems and Communication, Centre of Talented Training - PFIEV

First Class Honors with Congratulations of the Ministry of Education

EXPERIENCE

Carnegie Mellon University

2016 - Present

Research Fellow, Computer Science

Pittsburgh, PA, US

- · Automatic symbolic resource bound (e.g., time and memory) analysis of functional and imperative programs for detecting security vulnerability including time side-channel attacks, stack overflow, etc
- · Static analysis for probabilistic programs, e.g., automatic symbolic expected resource bound analysis such as execution time and memory usage

INRIA France

2014 - 2015

R&D Engineer

Rennes, France

- · Formal verification of probabilistic SystemC models using Statistical Model Checking
- · Probabilistic temporal assertion-based verification of SystemC models

INRIA France
Research Assistant
2011 - 2014
Rennes, France

- · Formal verification of the highly optimizing and industrial synchronous compiler, Signal, which is used in model-based design of real-time and safety-critical systems
- · Using translation validation approach to prove the preservation of clock semantics, data dependencies and value-equivalence for source code and the compiled programs using several techniques including model checking, theorem proving, graph transformation

Tech Propulsion Lab USA

Software Architect Saigon Branch, Vietnam

· Design and development of embedded mobile software on iOS and Android platforms

· Project management in the mobile development department

IBM Zurich Lab and ZISC

2008 - 2010

2010 - 2011

Research Assistant

Zurich. Switzerland

· Formally verifying and certifying the design of secure boot processes in IBM AIX mainframes

 $\cdot \ \ \text{Formalizing the boot process and its security properties using the language of the model checker Spin, Promela.}$

Verimag Lab

2007 - 2008

Internship

Grenoble, France

· Automated verification framework to prove formally the IND-CPA security property of asymmetric encryption schemes

· The framework represents the encryption schemes as frame in cryptographic π -calculus, and formalize the IND-CPA property as a equivalent relation between two frames

IBM Vietnam 2006 - 2007

Senior Software Engineer

Hanoi, Vietnam

Hanoi, Vietnam

· Working on text search engine of the IBM data base management DB2

FPT Software 2005 - 2006

Software Engineer

· Working on embedded systems for navigation

Security Systems, MISOFT

2003 - 2005

Software Developer

Hanoi, Vietnam

· Developing a distributed firewall as an operation system based on the package filtering library and the Linux kernel in C++ and Python

Hanoi University of Technology

2000 - 2003

Tutor

Hanoi, Vietnam

· Student teaching in Mathematics and Physics

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

- · Programming Languages. Strong knowledge: C/C++, OCaml Familiarity: Assembly, Java, Python
- · Toolchains. Strong knowledge: GCC, LLVM Compiler Infrastructure
- · Formal Methods & Modeling Languages. Strong knowledge: Synchronous Languages, Logics and Temporal Logics, Model Checking, Theorem Proving, Static Analysis Familiarity: Verilog, SystemC
- · Formal Method Tools. SPIN, SMV, UPAAL, PRISM, SMC Plasma Lab, Yices, Z3, Coq, Frama-C
- · Embedded Software Development. Familiarity: AVR, Arduino, RTLinux, FreeRTOS

LANGUAGES

English - Advance French - Advance Vietnamese - Mother-tongue

AWARDS

Ph.D scholarship, INRIA France

DEA scholarship from the French government, Université de Grenoble, France Masters scholarship from the Italian government, Politecnico di Milano, Italy Masters scholarship from SamSung company, ICU-KAIST, South Korea Scholarships from Hanoi University of Technology for excellent academic results